<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Konstantin Wirz</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Konstantin Wirz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 13:49:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://konstantin.wirz.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Graceful HTTP Server Shutdown in Go</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/posts/golang_graceful_shutdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 13:49:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/posts/golang_graceful_shutdown/</guid><description>Suppose we have a longer running operation in one of our http handler, perhaps a important transaction and if we just quit the application the transaction will be interrupted and some important data might be lost. How can we handle that? The solution is quite simple and well known - graceful shutdown and i am going to show you how to implement it in go.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started. At frist let&amp;rsquo;s implement a simple http server which responses with a bar if we are requesting a /foo</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:28:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/projects/</guid><description>[07/2021-present] - Vaillant Group DevOps Engineer (freelancer) API Developer Programme Aggegation of data from IoT devices, providing APIs to query the data
Tech Stack: azure, k8s, kafka, mongodb, java, spring boot, ELK, grafana, prometheus, helm, kustomize
[5/2020-6/2021] - MediaSaturn IT Services Senior Software Engineer (employee) Development of an order management platfrom Tech Stack: GCP, k8s, istio, kafka, mongodb, java, kotlin, grafana, prometheus, gitops with fluxcd, helm</description></item><item><title>Skills</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/skills/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:22:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/skills/</guid><description>Architecture &amp;amp; Concepts DevOps Configuration as Code GitOps Microservices REST Event Driven Design Distributed systems Languages, Operating Systems &amp;amp; Dev Tools Java Go Kotlin Gradle Maven GNU/Linux macOS Unix shell Javascript Platform, Container &amp;amp; Cloud Docker Kubernetes Kafka Google Cloud Platform Azure GutHub Terraform Helm Kustomize</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:20:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello World!</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/contact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 15:11:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/contact/</guid><description>send an email to konstantin@wirz.dev</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 14:58:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://konstantin.wirz.dev/about/</guid><description>DevOps engineer (freelancer) Passionated software engineer striving to build the right software the right way. Strong team player bringing a positive and motivated attitude. 15+ years of experience in backend software engineering for commerce, IoT, automotive and software industries.
&amp;hellip;available for new challenges in July 2022 (preferably somewhere close to Munich)
This site was generated using HUGO and an open source theme Coder via a GitHub action.</description></item></channel></rss>